Haseem M Isaac

Email: <u>haseemisaac@gmail.com</u>

Github: haseemisaac Linkedin: haseemisaac

A Computer Science undergraduate with **hands-on experience** of software development gained through the projects I've worked on. I am highly confident in my skills to work within a team. I have worked on projects with high level of complexity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SERVER-SIDE APPLICATIONS

- + Made a **chat bot** in Java using several libraries and by making use of various APIs which I later reprogrammed in NodeJS which is running in a **VPS**.
- + The chat bot currently has around **700~ users** all around the world. One of the hurdles that I had to overcome was the time zone offsets and DST changes that wasn't available for offline applications; there were only online APIs.
- + Experience in coding my own **APIs** in **NodeJS** and Python; one of which had in-house time zone, offset and DST detection using the latitude and longitude.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

+ I have made use of several **open source projects** so to give back to the community; I decided to design an integration for Discord with the Dialogflow (API.AI) which didn't exist and published on **GitHub**

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

+ Currently in the process of making an application using **React Native Framework** for both Android and iOS. I have previously used the **Ionic Framework** (Combined with AngularJS and Apache Cordova).

CLOUD SERVICES

+ Currently using the **AWS** services to run several of my applications in the cloud including VPS (EC2) instances and RDS database. I am also using **Google Cloud** and **OVH** to run VPS instances and several other services

CONCURRENT FUNCTIONAL/RELATIONAL PROGRAMING LANGUAGE

+ Bringing my professor's **22 years research** into fruition by making an interpreter for his concurrent **functional/relational programming language** called Aldwych.

H

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

+ Advanced – Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Intermediate – Python, TypeScript, PHP, SQL, Objective-C, Kotlin

EDUCATION

2016-Present - QUEEN MARY UNIVERSITY OF LONDON – UNDERGRADUATE DEGREE

- Computer Science BSc with Honours Achieved First Class in 1st Year (80%) and 2nd Year (77%)
- 2014-2016 NEWVIC SIXTH FORM COLLEGE BTEC EXTENDED DIPLOMA
 - D*D*D* Distinction in all 18 modules 420 UCAS Points
- + 2011-2014 LONDON EAST ACADEMY GCSE
 - 11 A-Cs in GCSE including English, Math and all 3 sciences

WORK EXPERIENCE

- + 2018-Present TEACHING ASSISTANT Several modules including Software Engineering and Database Systems
- + 2017-Present SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Creating server-side and client-side applications for organisations

AWARDS

+ 2017 - BP IMPERIAL HACKATHON

 Awarded the first prize of £3000 for successfully winning the Imperial College Hackspace hackathon sponsored by BP and run by Amazon which involved heavy use of voice activated technology such as Amazon's Alexa.

+ 2016 - PRINCIPAL'S AWARD FOR ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE

 During the NEWVIC ANNUAL AWARDS, I was honored to receive the highest academic award for providing outstanding effort and work throughout the 2 years.

POSITONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

+ 2016-PRESENT - COURSE REPRESENTATIVE - UNIVERSITY

• I am currently serving as a course representative for 3rd year Computer Science where I present **queries or complaints** made by my fellow students to academic staff.

+ 2014-2016 - STUDENT AMBASSADOR - COLLEGE

• Served as the student ambassador where I listened to the needs of the students and relay them to the necessary individuals so that the necessary actions are taken.